A Guide to the Richmond (Va.), Bureau of Permits and Inspections, Building permit architectural blueprints and specifications, 1907-1976
Library of Virginia
- Blueprint drawings, 1907-1950, 3167 sets of blueprints
  - Warehouses, 1908-1948
    - Warehouse - Permit Number: 28474, Warehouse and Bakery for The Great Atlantic & Pacific Tea Company, Address: 1700 Jefferson Davis Highway, 1947 (Folder 2648)
      Drawn by: Truscon Steel Products, Youngstown, Ohio; Contractor: N/A; Commissioned by: James J. DeBoy Inc.; Notes: James J. DeBoy Inc. own the building, while the Great Atlantic and Pacific Tea Company are the tenants.
    - Warehouse - Permit Number: 28752, Warehouse for John G. Kolbe, Address: 311-13 E. Main St., 1947 (Folder 2691)
      Drawn by: Thomas A. Whaples, Architect, 120A No. 8 St., Richmond, VA; Contractor: N/A; Commissioned by: John G. Kolbe; Notes:
    - Warehouse - Permit Number: 28840, [Warehouse], Address: 2516-18 Hermitage Rd., 1947 (Folder 2842)
      Drawn by: Butler Manufacturing Co.; Contractor: N/A; Commissioned by: H. B. Truslow; Notes: "two warehouses" is written on the outside of the plans.
    - Warehouse - Permit Number: 28812, Office & Warehouse, S. W. Corner of Roseneath and Leigh St., Richmond, VA for Consolidated Sales Co. Inc., Address: 1408 Roseneath Rd., 1947 (Folder 2840)
      Drawn by: H. Carl Messerschmidt, Architect, Mutual Building, Richmond VA; Contractor: N/A; Commissioned by: B. Jacobs & R. Klein; Notes:
    - Warehouse - Permit Number: 28804, [Warehouse], Address: 3014 W. Marshall St., 1947 (Folder 2751)
    - Warehouse - Permit Number: 34630A, Addition to Building No. 3406 Moore Street for Mr. I. L. Sutherland, Address: 3406 Moore St., 1947 (Folder 2814)
      Drawn by: H. Carl Messerschmidt, Architect, Mutual Building, Richmond VA; Contractor: N/A; Commissioned by: Irvin Sutherland; Notes:
    - Warehouse - Permit Number: 28688, Plant for Allied Distributors, 3300 Bl. Rosedale Ave., Address: 3308 Rosedale, 1947 (Folder 2803)
      Drawn by: Unsigned; Contractor: Muhleman and Kayhoe Contractors; Commissioned by: Allied Investment Corporation; Notes: Specifications are titled "Specifications for Office and Warehouse"
    - Warehouse - Permit Number: 28552, Office & Warehouse #957-59 Myers Street for A. R. Tiller Corporation, Address: 957-59 Myers, 1947 (Folder 2775)
      Drawn by: H. Carl Messerschmidt, Architect, Mutual Building, Richmond VA; Contractor: N/A; Commissioned by: A. R. Tiller Corp.; Notes:
    - Warehouse - Permit Number: 34513A, Addition to Warehouse, Tuckahoe Warehouse Corp., 9th St. West of Semmes Ave., Address: 9th St. W. of Semmes, 1947 (Folder 2745)
      Drawn by: Robert Mills, Architect, 1900 E. Franklin St.; Contractor: N/A; Commissioned by: Tuckahoe Warehouse; Notes:
    - Warehouse - Permit Number: 34611A, Proposed Addition to the A.B.C. Warehouse, Broad and Harrison Sts., Address: Harrison & Broad, 1947 (Folder 2816)
      Drawn by: E. M. Hastings, Chief Engineer, Richmond Fredericksburg and Potomac Railroad Company; Contractor: N/A; Commissioned by: R. F. & P. Railroad; Notes:
    - Warehouse - Permit Number: 29886, Proposed Warehouse for H. C. Cockrell Storage Co., Address: 1200 Dinwiddie Ave., 1948 (Folder 3162)
      Drawn by: Unsigned; Contractor: N/A; Commissioned by: A. C. Cockrell; Notes:
    - Warehouse - Permit Number: 29616, Warehouse, Address: 1600 Jefferson Davis Hwy., 1948 (Folder 2923)
      Drawn by: Wheeling Corrugating Co., Wheeling, W. Va., Building Products Division; Contractor: N/A; Commissioned by: Wheeling Corrugating; Notes: Includes office space.
    - Warehouse - Permit Number: 29719, Addition to Warehouse for Sash Door & Glass Corp., 6th & Stockton Streets, Address: 516 Stockton, 1948 (Folder 3017)
      Drawn by: Unsigned; Contractor: N/A; Commissioned by: Miller Mfg. Co.; Notes:
    - Warehouse - Permit Number: 29767, Warehouse and Office for Richmond Food Stores, Address: 2522 Hermitage Rd., 1948 (Folder 3038)
      Drawn by: Unsigned; Contractor: N/A; Commissioned by: Richmond Food Stores, Inc.; Notes:
    - Warehouse - Permit Number: 29377, Warehouse Building for Southside Feed & Seed Co., Inc., 2105-07 Hull Street, Richmond, VA, Address: 2031-33 Hull St., 1948 (Folder 3130)
      Drawn by: H. Carl Messerschmidt, Architect, 1124 Mutual Building, Richmond VA; Contractor: N/A; Commissioned by: W. W. & J. A. Chewing; Notes:
    - Warehouse - Permit Number: 35176A, Alterations and Additions to Warehouse and Office for United States Plywood Corporation, Address: E. 7th & Gordon Sts., 1948 (Folder 3112)
      Drawn by: Frank P. Cartwright, Prof. Eng., Canandaigua, NY; Contractor: N/A; Commissioned by: U. S. Plywood; Notes:
    - Warehouse - Permit Number: 29821, E. K Vietor and Co., Inc., 1800 Semmes Ave., Tobacco Open Storage Shed, Address: 1800 Semmes, 1948 (Folder 3104)
      Drawn by: Unsigned; Contractor: N/A; Commissioned by: E. K. Vietor Co.; Notes:
    - Warehouse - Permit Number: 29828, Brick Warehouse for R. S. Montgomery, Inc., N. E. Corner Roseneath Rd. and Rockbridge St., Richmond, VA, Address: 1801 Roseneath Rd., 1948 (Folder 3088)
      Drawn by: Unsigned; Contractor: N/A; Commissioned by: R. S. Montgomery, Inc.; Notes:
    - Warehouse - Permit Number: 35110A, Specification Drawings of Proposed Additions and Alterations to Virginia Electric & Power Co., Storage & Loading Facilities, Stafford Ave., Richmond, VA, Address: Stafford and Parkwood, 1948 (Folder 3054)
      Drawn by: C. C. & F. C. Welton; Contractor: N/A; Commissioned by: Virginia Electric and Power Co.; Notes:
- , 1950-1970
  Accession 41023 is loosely arranged by the month and year.
- Records on Microfilm, 1907-1976, 240 microfilm reels
  Arranged into three subseries
  - Index Books 1907-1970, 12 microfilm reels
    The index books dating from 1907-1941 are arranged chronologically and hereunder in two ways: by the last name of the applicant for the permit and by the location of the proposed project (street address or intersection). Beginning in 1941, the indices are arranged only by location of the project.
    - (Reel 193)
      Contents
      1915 INDEX - By Name
      1907 - 1909 INDEX - By Name
      1907 INDEX - By Location
      1909 INDEX - By Location
      1910 - 1911 INDEX - By Name
      1910 INDEX - By Location
      1912 INDEX - By Name
      1911 INDEX - By Location
      1912 INDEX - By Location
      1913 INDEX - By Name
      1913 INDEX - By Location
      1914 INDEX - By Location
      1915 INDEX - By Location
      1916 INDEX - By Name
      1916 INDEX - By Location
      1917 INDEX - By Name
      1917 - 1918 - INDEX - By Location
      1918 INDEX - By Name
      1918 - 1920 INDEX - By Location
      1919 INDEX - By Name
      1920 INDEX - By Name
      1921 INDEX - By Name
      1921-1923 INDEX - By Location
      1924 INDEX - By Name
      1925 INDEX - By Name
      1924 - 1926 INDEX - By Location
    - (Reel 194)
      1926 INDEX - By Name
      1927 INDEX - By Name
      1928 INDEX - By Name
      1927 - 1929 INDEX - By Location
      1929 INDEX - By Name
      1930 INDEX - By Name
      1931 INDEX - By Name
      1932 INDEX - By Name
      1933 INDEX - By Name
      1930 - 1933 INDEX - By Location
      1934 INDEX - By Name
      1935 INDEX - By Name
      1934 - 1935 INDEX - By Location
      1936 INDEX - By Name
      1937 INDEX - By Name
      1938 INDEX - By Name
      1939 INDEX - By Name
      1936 - 1940 INDEX - By Location
      1940 INDEX - By Name
      1941 INDEX - By Name
      1942 INDEX - By Name
    - (Reel 195)
      1943 INDEX - By Name
      1944 INDEX - By Name
      1941 - 1944 INDEX - By Location
      1944 INDEX - By Location (Aug. - Dec.)
      1945 INDEX - By Location
      1946 INDEX - By Location
      1947 INDEX - By Location
      1948 INDEX - By Location
      1949 INDEX - By Location
      1950 INDEX - By Location
      1951 INDEX - By Location
      1952 INDEX - By Location
      1953 INDEX - By Location
      1954 INDEX - By Location
      1955 INDEX - By Location
      1956 INDEX - By Location
      1957 INDEX - By Location
      1958 INDEX - By Location
      1959 INDEX - By Location
      1960 INDEX - By Location
      1961 INDEX - By Location
      1962 INDEX - By Location
      1963 INDEX - By Location
      1964 INDEX - By Location
      1965 INDEX - By Location
      1966 INDEX - By Location
      1967 INDEX - By Location
      1968 INDEX - By Location
      1969 INDEX - By Location
      1970 INDEX - By Location
    - (Reel 196)
      Alterations and Repairs - Index - 1907 - 1923
    - (Reel 197)
      Alterations and Repairs - Index - 1924 - 1934
    - (Reel 198)
      Alterations and Repairs - Index - 1935 - 1955
    - (Reel 199)
      Alterations and Repairs - Index - 1956 - 1970
    - (Reel 200)
      Demolitions - Index - Permit 1 - 71 (1937 - 1949)
    - (Reel 201)
      Demolitions - Index - Permit 972 - 2057 (1949 - 1956)
    - (Reel 202)
      Demolitions - Index - Permit 2058 - 3243 (1956 - 1960)
    - (Reel 203)
      Demolitions - Index - Permit 3244 - 4899 (1960 - 1965)
    - (Reel 204)
      Demolitions - Index - Permit 4900 - 5800 (1965 - 1969)
  - Building Permit Application Forms 1907-1976, 12 microfilm reels
    Arranged by permit number
    Individual items are identified by there City of Richmond building permit number
    - (Reel 275)
      Building Inspection Permit Forms 1 - 1319
  - Architectural Drawings and Specifications 1907-1976, 12 microfilm reels